<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ecology on Beck</title>
    <link>/categories/ecology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ecology on Beck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>beck@frecologic.com (Beck Frydenborg)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>beck@frecologic.com (Beck Frydenborg)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/ecology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision Making and Distributions</title>
      <link>/blog/decisions_distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>beck@frecologic.com (Beck Frydenborg)</author>
      <guid>/blog/decisions_distributions/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes in environmental regulation, we are unable to find a clear cause-effect relationship between a known stressor and a known response due to confounders. This is a common problem when attempting to determine acceptable nutrient regimes for some systems. For example, Florida Department of Environmental Protection (FDEP) was required to promulgate Numeric Nutrient Criteria for estuaries as the result of a lawsuit, yet no straightforward cause-effect relationship could be found for Total Nitrogen (TN) and/or Total Phosphorus (TP) leading to excess Chlorophyll a, which in turn lead to submerged aquatic vegetation (SAV) die-off resulting in the loss of this key habitat for these highly productive systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Year in Review</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>beck@frecologic.com (Beck Frydenborg)</author>
      <guid>/blog/2017-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>Happy 2018! I’ve rebuilt the website with the Beautiful-Hugo theme.
It’s a new year, and one of my goals is to actually blog more consistently. With that in mind, here is a “better late than never” (but still later than it should be) post in which I look back and reflect on the past year.
Borrowing a format I saw on The Lab and Field Blog, here is my 2017 by the numbers:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>