<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>human health on Beck</title>
    <link>/categories/human-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in human health on Beck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>beck@frecologic.com (Beck Frydenborg)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>beck@frecologic.com (Beck Frydenborg)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/human-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 and other Pandemics</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-19-and-other-pandemics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>beck@frecologic.com (Beck Frydenborg)</author>
      <guid>/blog/covid-19-and-other-pandemics/</guid>
      <description>I’ve seen this graphic from this blog going around, and while I agree that it is pretty and visually interesting, I find it mostly ineffective for communicating the magnitudes of pandemics over time. Our eyes and brains have a difficult time comparing the volume of spheres compared to a line on a bar chart. Additionally, the image is three dimensional in perspective, which further obfuscates direct comparisons.
Pandemics
So since I’m in quarentine, I decided to make a more basic image that allows one to compare magnitudes better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Health Criteria Part One</title>
      <link>/blog/human-health-criteria-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>beck@frecologic.com (Beck Frydenborg)</author>
      <guid>/blog/human-health-criteria-part-one/</guid>
      <description>Recently in Florida, there has been some controversy over an update to Human Health Criteria (HHC) that the Florida Department of Environmental Protection (FDEP) promulgated concerning acceptable levels for 88 carcinogens in ambient water and seafood. Most notably, many environmental activists are concerned that historic numbers for several substances are proposed to increase. Many blame FDEP’s use of a probabilistic model instead of the previously used deterministic model, and this theme was repeated in the press:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>